work
that's a great question he has a lot of
files
i typically get you wondered what farm
if you want to break them up into some
other organization that's okay too
if easy for me if you have one more
files which is god
astore entry to topple which one
you don't mind
that's exactly right
there's lots of tools that let me do you
have to do it
are different scott collision between
the two and i think cc
yes i can easily how what's new
i'm hoping that
soon with a few version control stuff
see what you see
high-tech universe trauma like an alpha
version control for your stuff and i
have to worry about you hangin in
filthy and call it that you just work on
it
and then when i have
was doable
yet so you don't have to do anything
special quick
were still
the troubles are so many concepts that i
think are helpful
it's which ones aren't you guys first
and trust fund
the only thing i care is if recent days
that we have a colossal a sea of star
entry with one-star
and we admire title is going to see that
the date stamp and i want to see if
colin bday
that's it
minute depends on the person what's
going to help for free or a and if
you're doing mostly paper
if that's what you're best at then
that's okay too
and while i take it take away too much
free time from that but i want leaf
think about the idea attract one
the paper is really
pretty pain in the short term lately
victories
like next petrol paper
here
yeah
this opera called papers for a while he
won't do that
no i mean i could retreat and that
with that
it's far deeper reviewers pretty well in
the short term
but when you had ten years built up
and you say
i'm looking for that one thing i did
awhile back
it gets very hard
quick report on everything that you've
done your career
this point for next job interview
uh...
you know that it's hard
my hope is that if you go up and working
on file for her
work like you could have separate off
which class you could
mix it up but then
one use committed towards all the files
and a second
rally
hoping to spark
right so let's jump in today to some
announcements first one
is that created at google group
so we have a good group for the class
i've made a public so people who aren't
necessarily in the class here can join
too
we have some folks that no other places
that are watching that the classes
canisters for however you guys want to
do it if you want to discuss or ask
questions here or what
you can discuss things with each other
here
dot so we find
we can also completely ignore that's it
didn't cost us anything the setup
and know that hike if you're doing a
research project a couple people
and you don't mind it being public you
can put up for these
for any project like you are the one for
summer hydro and you get there
how you can create a group in and
discuss things
specifically in terms of
being able to have discussions on
homework for concepts or if you guys
you know her rights and the full
confusing you all could figure out what
mature version of
business card
and i've also created an
four each lecture that i've done
uh... what goes there really boring
what ghost isn't about the post more
than a a place for
if you find price does
you're welcome to some of them in your
log files that's fine too
the folks in the rest of the class won't
see those until i do something about him
through here if you post a comment
then you it'll go in there mccann
discuss they can figure out
what's going on with the crippling so
feel free to use these comments if you
find typo or to have a question on the
homework
out so that you know when these things
get
so that one for each other
classes
going back away from it
re-entry arbitrary
it's more about
just a few wilson write notes
triple c
and is pulling him the ones we have so
far
eleven out so far
and big news of the week is that steve
jobs just passed away
hopefully you all have been able to get
the or file for today
and the cluster three
underclass slash twelve
and make sure you've got the word file
inside a backlash today if your work
while or somewhere else
when you create a file and you work with
your work between next and and i paper
on shelf
you're gonna get confused for sure
so this way
if your files and there is open that's
exp max is pack to be right thing that
directory
the help us keep track of things
we're gonna start off with some more
setup
no at this point were pretty close to
power in a really starting to actual
geospatial fun stuff like projections
and huge yassin
working with more data
wait a little bit more
to get you max really happy and you guys
are learning
all fun and stuff so far
will dig into setting up a lot debates
uh...
i thought i fight on
andy max
so that
you can run pipe uncle from pretty much
where it will be in this class
nick what's it was shipped out and and
feel free to use the same
mechanism in your lecture notes if you
want to
sold tab on setup
setting up your editor
startup you max and
for starts
just to get going
if you do a meta acts
meta x
server
dash start
this is going to create a special server
lessons
request to added files
if you're writing about if you can
actually have the bass cryptology max
that
do you want to add something
handbag was gone
approval it now and then passed back and
continue on
this from my iphone especially
where you're working with an effect on
shell if you're working on a script you
can say i need to go and get some more
to go ahead and hit enter
in my case was already running
medha x server dash toward
tell you what is the future for about
the cemetery maxell is always running
it was a very much
and you know it's working in a moment
when the transit
this is going to set up it'll be next to
be listening for requested files
sheehy open up
paternal
and if you say email x
clients
read me dot t_ exp
they'll be the best will do everything
from class twelve
anything is that uh...
if you sent me a help question about
homework or something in the class
it's really helpful if you work in the
terminal two copy
everything including apart because it
tells me
which happier in a fast
software firm looking over your shoulder
at
had something you're working on a class
and if you have to see if you're a great
spot
seer their terminal
from the kremlin you had not run
hypochlorite like that you're just using
regular batch
t
if you hit enter
he should see something like this where
your demat pops to the front
and the terminal so i was waiting for
even server here
throat the cuban cure
he's actually no
yep and do their command i have on the
whiteboard
panetta server start
that acts
server dot store
so now go back over here
so you got it running and used by
running that extra per starring
restarted the server which is ok
for not going to your family
and safety max
clients
space
next lamar and amp
space read me dot t_ xti
tonight here in nj
staring at a point really dot t_ extinct
soviet tyranny max that's two will be
losing out on the buffer below one
simple thing
so now do you own
maddox
and that's pulled down all ltte
and x
aliquot and pfizer reductions
press center
now go back to come on time on that next
point
anti p max quiet
space
press pass
and then a c_n_n_-time
remi dot t_ xti
got a couple things going on here
here
does not appear to be
stuff in there just to control its one
and i'd like to come home
at the apparent
and on that
click in this weekend
it's off busy doing something so it's
going or you delivery
so in this file
at whatever you want like
and were to say this
control x
control s
and now you can type
the commands to say hands-on edginess in
terms of max clients and that's going to
be
c dash acts
and my signed operative tight
the figure
control acts
and then the number sign
and it will disappear on your right now
it's setup unlike
i have my answer to not disappear of
i'll get you guys just a second
hope we can talk to the phones
and still have this specific one
and won the dean
the max
clients
uh...
see you on this command that after
you've gotten some facts that you do
this
so now appear internal you should see
you're really dot
fidel rent you almost the same thing
inside of i fight on
we're going to you
this is worse than you got ripped up
there's the export editor equals m_x_
clients
copied outline
and paste it into your terminal
the press enter
it's gone you going to determine
to control you
to dallas tassel
and see how you have a really
interesting
snake anti-tax pastry
so caps
c_a_c_
space capital are tab
so you do contribute hoboken silly
for one year in prison off a bomb
surreal hold on patrol
pressed for her
acts
you would go
annual to your account shifts three
why
and so now you've been
betsy expound that file superpages
pastoralize final
so capital are in in time
center
they're looking at the corner father and
keep quiet
to go ahead and start by python
so it should look familiar
will do at its
hello
worlds
dot pine
so any time there and i played on shelf
quest we have this all setup
if you want to treating you
i don't scripts
you can just typed at it
hello you know what every year scrip
name is
and
if you were at sandia existing companies
have fallen
and press enter
and you're now adding hello world top
five
amended directly trolex to this point
that
and then control acts and then the beat
just switch poppers
so i can see my notes again
if u don't like to know you can just
returned from up here
so we've done this
and hello world
and let's put something in it
was to say
henry a democrat
this command great here
control acts and the pound
you can or not
you have a quick afterwards after you've
done that
hello world
so i'm gonna press control acts
and the pound
if you ask me do i want to save the file
if i haven't seen it already
and tied yes
and what you're here
so if i at this farm distance again here
hello world
and i go over to my key max
and
and the common for example
now fire on control acts
and power
that's great if you go to save it it's
one of the things that look if you could
use a computer long-time serb stating
that even thinking about it
that he said yes and it runs your script
so i think you have a call-in what if it
is a close the buffer and in that kind
of a buffer with the calendar from you
making a log entry art
support yet
no it doesn't default to give you a
calendar right afterwards
dot dot says word on adding to the
client sore thumb through this
so that doesn't say
cousins they save what it says is and on
and then for
this expands
so you need to be in the key maxwell
within their and down to the control
acts an account
jeff st
turn out to a control acts
and hold on shift in press three
democrats control anne
david
here are the messages i wouldn't worry
about the messages but
your controlled soon
to control its warm to make yourself up
one window
known to you
control acts
and then the pound character
shifts three
so now says he wants a depressed wine
and if you go up your terminal you see
the it clinic and principles sudhir taxi
is finished he came back to hear clothes
that file
ever in the program first
wedding we'd daddy
your attitude your initial simplifying
and say i want to make a python file so
at the file name
if there is healthy mexico edit this
file
and we don't have any seo candidate and
then tells i fight on okay go ahead and
i think mom
there's no way we had a tax inside of my
pipeline saving on this
this is not creating a file or edit
modify asks for quality work on it yet
i think it was easy
a lot of times and you'll start getting
it tickets confusing at first just let
it
cargo pascual and
sort of its orbit without trying to
worry too much about the details
controls even click
no no it's just returned from inside the
maximum start of a q_v_c_ was super star
testing
alright i'm sure you have any way sir
and fight on so i apologize for them to
be lots of
options here
we are now back to set up your
environment so that you have you max
setup all time for this
so open up
you're talking that spot which is in
your home directory sis's do control
acts
control
and then you had to get it till the
slashdot you max
then you're going to be created
so if you went through the process
hopefully you've got
something like this in there
air ticket tax that inside
this down below here
air interface that up into your
documents filed and save it so squeamish
something here
at the bottom of your file yet
good acting that way
doesn't actually as long as the key in
the middle of something else itself
okay are you opening up a dot e maxwell
so control extra-large
so if you look at here
florida shippers for correlates
there should be a fury in there
so if you're headed your he max file
without the thought
and it's not gonna work
there has to be a doctor
did you have a tax on the bottom
so now we're gonna go at it one more doc
file
get set up
we'll put up your dot bash carseat
and you're correct close your eyes to
all the craziness is in there
and go to the bottom of that file
apple wine
down here
europe but that the bottom of your batch
artsy export editor equals imax client
we did that once in your terminal
and the next time you have a turmoil
that was then disappear and not be
available
syedalisafvi editor
every time to sort of a terminal
district runs and will set your error to
the imax quiet
today to talk about your backyard for
you
humanistic
uh... ok not a problem that you can just
to easy way to go to buffers at stop
them
go back to your dot imax
and there was a love story i think it's
nato sardinia you're definitely takes to
get the trolex control that's in there
and i asked her
you're having a backup file into the
pounds in there
those talents means that you know i've
seen the file you want to be anything
i weighed what for
blacks in the next day
printer
and you wanna open up nor
the actual work files posted the backup
file
twelve
sadat open on the grounds of permanent
just open up the actual
year twelve o'clock in the world few
very carefully open files because a lot
of other stuff around
all right we're gonna skip directs the
configuration for the short cuts
because i want you guys moving towards
icon stuff which is more fun
and setting up the imax
so now at this point if you've done that
needed quick every start booking a
terminal andy max
so here it says
joint children at a process
i'm missing you know because i i
actually don't wanna lockout
aboard and set up at your if you get
this officer yes
providing quick
and restart your remarks
so then doing exit
out of your ipod iphone
and exit out of the terminal
now pleaded
if i had something running in the
background which i've been such an idiot
it's ok just
kelly obviously
then cd
class
so i'm in our bromide pipeline
highland
certain already checked our work
cameron pile of and c_d_f_
yet intersect
there's a module called operation summer
alas
then we can tell you how s dot
environments
and we're lookin dictionaries more in
the future of uh...
so we're gonna run high pipeline in the
class directory
right there
you can give you haven't tried you at
all the time just to make myself
get habit
parma forget the future and wonder why
we can't plot
determine yep
wanted to do that
what does it's causing it's all revoking
p plans to make
poor and double check so that for now on
forever out from the class can you come
back to stop all be set up
and if it's not set up and you're going
to be confused the next class
so we're attested to read one academic
year
press enter if you've got that line
should taking max clients
and honey important or lessen the ls
environment you looking
hoping this decision next point
you're getting a whole bunch of stuff
that deals with the offerings include
you can type
elapse and i will tell you something
about what is convening you get a sense
of it as we go
so here was using it without
learning too much about alexis it's a
double check
so if you don't have any max plan to
take a quick look at your system and
figure out what's wrong
let's look at your bachelors in
sand
lol
it
uh... that's just me
if at the bottom so statement grew
some agreement
teased lightly here a destination equal
signs of illness
insisted that williston fellas
controls needed for themselves
controlled senior no influence control
let's say hilliard protocols for
internal should have it
so open about terminally here
feels like i've missed attacks up there
needed terminal
typewriter on her c_d_ into the class
directory first and then
now eitan
and now you getting a fair
and i'll try running that command with
the uh... they won't the center
yes also
so now i've got my bike run setup annie
mac setup
so we're gonna work on the script today
brit a call at first occupied
sofa going here we say
addicts
first dot fine
press printer
going to bring this up and your control
excuse split
control xbeats
and switch back to my
notes
so i can see
and verleger type in there
or you can copy and paste
usurping
eunji pipeline print
so this is
our first recovered i worked on ameri
keep going on the same file throughout
fought today
the credit card in this text
you have an area dot he maxwell
so i'm going to simply in the criminal
conduct this after class
listing
t fertility dancer remax again
so now you have an error message in
their kids and i'll go ahead and i think
on friday night
here and and getting actor princy rain
card creator something
in the middle class position
okay so say that file
and now
if your control acts pounds
this time the file more disappears
because i don't something that's very
fun to have your file the spirit and
energy
so you're done and then it disappears
with you guys
one of those settings that we set up
folder to not get rid of for overtime
because i've
in getting ready for class that drove me
nuts about two seconds
so now we've got are for stop by the
wreaking used for the rest of class
and explain to a little bit about how
programs that drive
deleted shell scripts with a pound
bang
bash
if this is the first line of your
scripts this says go off and run this
command
with fast
an impasse at all the text of the rest
of the file
in python php
brings a slightly different
usr
he and the disintegrate on here that's
also pricing
but then you pass a python
what this does is that some people on
their systems have multiple pythons
if it got like python two point seven
point one three hand two point five in
all sorts of special pillow talk by
phone
this lets people control
which python gets used by the fault it's
as good a brother first fight on from
your path
and if people are fancy they can play
with their patent genes which python
it doesn't matter
and people often just hard for the
pipeline
that's typically have stuff i think you
said this is the official line to use
for the first one to five points for
turning it around
so just copy this one
don't worry too much of the bills if you
really want no more you can read
the man
of u_n_d_p_
and it's very strange sounding program
but basically that's what this does for
this it this is the first one is for a
concert please go on python and pass it
the rest of the text in the file
question users
that's needed if he gets run as a script
if you see i know servers poppers
remained to add it
that means it
various nothing else waiting
sodium explains
there can be multiple ones running
around
and has a list of all the files that you
want to add it
at means there's no more left
it's not very exciting because we're
leading one of the time
these tools have all sorts of extra
fifty features
can be used ever using only a small bits
of their powers
and for those of you to fit your screen
savers too often
there is a screen saver singer setting
had its
system
preferences
screensaver
and you can say screensaver not to lock
when it turns on
because
well we're not really protecting a
thank-you valuable computer
so we can
go back over here and we can actually do
cat for stoplight
and you'll see your program and i think
that if you want to run
anything so ella special
there's my first are applied
any insight about bike then you can see
iran
and first
if you could say for sure for stuff i
think both the more so there's first or
first up five
and has run command will go up and run a
python script for you
cap allies like dot
captured arms a file to the spirit
i we're gonna skip for a little bit
let's go get some python because we
spend too much time factor max here
somewhat
let's go continue alma darling files
were quite often before
cabin there we're going to take a look
inside of our reading a file fight on
if you control c control c inspired this
little window it's going to write back
out facts
last time we headed out csd route fight
on
this is the same kind of thing in terms
of
if you just run that it's gonna
to be doing ls dot shelved
there's no data dot csd in there
if we run this control c
control c
we fight yes the one that i let the code
block
wherein in
the person's right inside of the begin
enter here
it gives you no results
unsatisfying bud
if we go back here doing alice dot
showing i python window
we now have a dinner dot csd
you could also copied it from there
class eleven directory
the trouble is there's about how
different ways we can create this file
so that way we just press two characters
and meet up at the file again
take a quick because again before we
move on period dot csd
well then zero three lines of are
comma-separated value files is
super important data
right so what's klotz
we were
doing something like this we were uh...
doing it
datafile opening
and then we were
uh... red-line one of the time down here
so we can say
datafile equals open
the uh... dot csd
for brad gets tried his picture you can
read it a final city that dot
datafile thought
red-line never pressing tab
so make sure you can open that file flap
that three doesn't fail
and his they've read line
and so i was going to warn you guys that
when you see this
this is me or working through the
commands oppressed tab it gives you the
options if you try to run this line
right here
it's gonna fail
so that's gonna
have a patch of year it doesn't know
what the heck that is
don't worry about one ashley here is
just that
unit at the right thing unfortunately
line
and anytime you
want to run a function
in the news parentheses and we made both
for putting arguments in there which is
what we did with the
the commander open stuff
but what goes in there are the arguments
that function things that we get it
about what we want to do
so if you read a line
you'll get back the first one the file
we'll do it again
red-lining
red-line
groups is where we left off with the
what the heck with that
so now we're back to where we were last
time
and will try some more
playing with
opening file so let's try a different
way every map file
simona copy
so we're gonna reopen the file
which faces takes it back to the
beginning says if everyone in the file
by reopening it
and datafile
read lines
now it looks almost the same
but that s is pretty important
this is going to resolve the winds at
once
which is pretty eighty
c dot the loop through and know how many
lines or are you could just go ahead and
run that so they're all there
each dealer open
so see how ive gone seventeen
their articles open
set up a trade it again
i'll get nothing atlas
that wasn't very excited because we
didn't say that they've any place
so let's do
the open yet again so on number twenty
i'm going to go ahead open the file
amenorrhea runners
datafile read lines at all say
lines equals
that so i'll save it into a variable
recommends a print lines
so now we have a list of all of our
lines of data
now realizes is pretty handy but if you
have a hundred thousand or a million
lines to read
it's good friend love them all into
memory in your machine is going to get
very slow
so this isn't the preferred way to read
it in the long run it's a great way to
get started
treated in fairfield
you can totally do that yes
i'll be perfect
very advanced and calls
australia
probably is a deal
so they look at those once we have a
list like we have a for a meeting to say
lines of zero
and look at the first one
wind one week at the next one we can go
back and get
zero again
and it's not lost
but we have some trouble never getting
more than we expected
and defect
function that the extremes called strip
that removes white space and the wind so
anything with the space character or a
tablet
or a new line
we can get rid of those
so they do that again and will do
strip
and then she presses we're gonna run
this function called strip online's
and notice
there's two
blank lines right here
thirsty right there
but if you look down here after twenty
six there's just one so cooperative one
of our plan clients in our strength
and you can see those blank lines are
actually print appears swatch and skin
are
so what we can do that for example if we
want to pullout
done
acts in the white for example the left
and right we could use what
definite split like we did before
it's just a few of white-space
whereas we want to do it on the comma
so we can pass in this argument saying
please put but
use the comic characters let up our
string for us
if you've got
you may receive it split into a small
list here that contains one call my to
you in in this
unfortunately wine
now you can change things together
we had this nice trip command here
where we strips the line got rid of that
extra newline
and then we can split after that
now is a little complicated
and look for your point out the
differences
so here
we split and we have a new line stuck in
there
here we split it and there's no new line
so we have a nice clean less of
are different fields
so what happens is that runs everything
here first
and what he's done the strep effendi
adds on to that and runs what on the
results from the sky
book is using
but will see is a couple times when you
kind of ad on functions and you can keep
doing more stuff to history
so if you look at my notes i actually
have a
yanks
you could stick it altogether gets
confusing
let's go ahead and now
take this text in this block
copycats
everything in here
cemented w once you've highlighted it
mandu control x to you
control xbeats
i've got a process less necks which i
don't want amid tab
can you give me a list of buffers
the series is being
probably different from you might have
icalendar or something else
what we want is this file call for
stockpile you can click on it or we can
type
first and pressed out
your weight he can do this is quicken
the windows get something else here and
you go to buffers
and select
should be first headings their for she's
up there
signficant first
if you already got a figure all set
and paste in
all that stuff with a control line
that you're feeling really uncomfortable
with
unites a patient like this at this point
go back and watch those videos again
the idea there if you can watch them
a couple that has been asked me
questions twenty watch them or
of some questions
on the uh...
eugene page
and we can discuss
was giving you trouble in terms of use
acts
algeria control x one to make it one
window
now you have a attacks we can go back
and remember the run commands we can
type ron
for stop i
animals you everything that we send
saved in this file
except for
i did something that intend to
and i got hello world only
which means
there are some stars down the bottom
down here
co-star say here to say
so need to save control x control us
and if you do this you should see a
whole bunch of stuff come out
so when i was showing
there was just different ways of doing
the same thing
and i missed during this pretty simple
breaking up for you guys
so i'm sorry
this is actually what happened to show
you guys right here
thoroughgoing curator ballpark herbal
so let me go ahead and do that
one by one or more
for watch this culture
so we have our lines
and from there within saline equals
winds and we can pick a
also grab the first lines of zero
with a square brackets
will print line
so one comment too
now we can also massive line equals wine
strip
can get rid of that you want to have a
rich is blank lines here
sinatra prep line
we get a much shorter
repressive print
we don't have to go in there we just got
this one verses to you
we've got rid of our new line
hedges step-by-step
from there we can say
fields
equals wind dot split
break it up by the common
and then to see what's in fields you can
either type prints feels or just type
fields and i fight on chill
you'll see there it's
one commenting
submitted on the notes a little bit
farther
and let's learn about four weeks
predicament
michelle and they were touchy into if
you put a space the wrong place the
world blew up
let's go ahead and play with some for
leaks
indict by pancho
so it's going to enter a couple times
give myself some mental space
pc just tons and tons of the stuff
sometimes it
nuns the brain so what's a four item in
and we'll give it a list
one com a three
six
nine
now this is a reminder that you can
stick a list
any type of object can be analysts said
that really matter
and
the four lou
stops with the but colin
that's the definition of a outer loop
and then afro presenter
and it's getting then ask us for what
goes inside of the world
and you're now they hate the trick is
part of haifong
this is different then most programming
languages
icon cares about how you win dent you're
taxed
if you in touch with the tab verses a
space
it thinks of it is a different block
it's actually forcing you to write
pretty cold
and for those of us who have to do with
too many years of not very pretty cold
uh... makes us happy
but able fight you a couple times and
beginning to get used to it
i pi quotas for us invented four spaces
that's that
it's not required how many spaces before
as the recommended numbers basis intends
to create beginning about you
so save print item
and if you press the enter
you now
waves hectare connects things that
happened through each wing
if we're going we have to give it
aligned without
indentation cypress
presenter twice
travel and our lives and running
so let's try that with our file
will save my file
equals open
fear god csd
so this issue as you get the former
colleague data file you can call
whatever you want
if his descriptive it's better if it's
random characters that will work with is
confusing
the nice thing about files
is that they
have the same property of the lesson
that you can't keep going through it you
get the next item until the end
so as do four
line
in my file
three or four loop
and what's gonna happen is he's tried to
deliver
before it was going to go us
my file for the next line
because they could be a nice things
please return it
and let's just go ahead and project
print line
so again to finish that will be in a
press enter twice
we're gonna suffer from that same
problem of printing
without extra line in there so there's a
new line
attached to each line and they were also
printing out west falls in line
so its review that with this trip
line dot strep
so here i think the uparrow
so it's kinda got rid of this
little prompting that they meant to have
for
typing
no cases in that the akimax window so
you can see it
what it looked like inside of a file
words
more natural
some individual exp
switch over to my first thought pauline
middle do amanda greater than two top to
bottom
and will paste that in there
patrol y
so if you see here at presenter
it takes you down to the next line has
invented still on the four lip so we
could save print
you may be some dashes or something
adventure and that
go back to the beginning to the right
services prints
for example
so we'll go to this loop
and tell us some of the file
then it finishes that moved by not being
invented anymore
terminal sprints dot
kia
the pipeline here last
i can write like that to you except for
that's perjury
so sometimes it's ok but typically it'll
just be confusing
soltero at died in here so will have a
prince
dash says
go back here and say
and see
humphrey admired for section works
don't do the darndest to enter after
that
now you don't see anything because
astronauts file again
everything about beginning close to that
so my file equals open dot do not see a
speedy pressed enter
and now to go back up
so that the apparel to get that come in
again
sophia fairly
presenter
twice three times and there we've got it
and then we're going to this would be
like prints
done and that would be the same as what
we typed in our
her skirt down here skies
that's it for today guys
the better you are back
the faster you will be
and when you get really good at this
stuff
people will be totally blown away with
what you can do
hikes in the back of
meetings at nasa
and i'm listed the conversation and i
control sometimes the screens around the
room
and people talk about a concept and
figures will just appear on the screen
as per gallon
and it kinda freaks out the managers but
that's the kind of things you can do
with things like you maximize python
where when you get really good at this
as you think your stuff grass can pop up
you can build figures
really cranky today too fast
and be able to keep thinking more about
what date is unless about mechanics
so the more you learn about the max the
faster you gonna get processing data and
the combination by python and i thought
lebanese max is going to give the
ability to
specially if you're on a ship
and that ship is costing you
you know twenty dollars every minute to
be out there which is not unreasonable
so imagine taking out we all go out of
your pocket every minute
putting on the table that's what we pay
for ships
so it may not feel like that when you
receive that's what's happening is that
money's going away going into gasoline
paying for the crew and uh... meals that
you need
so being faster this stuff will actually
make a big difference in what you can do
at sea
to be able to take a quick peek at the
data what stuff up fast
will make a big difference of how much
you get done
if you get to the point where urine
the class here for summer hydro
you don't have very much time you've got
act two weeks to do everything
and being able to see that tight
stationed here right away and make a
plot of its he was going on and evaluate
it quickly means you know right away
with regard to deter bacteria and
wouldn't go on
anencephaly help people up in the past
in this class being
hijacked by the data so
give it a go preachers videos post
questions on our on their own
alternatives and as best i can
and if you guys have some questions that
are